Now in order to go further with Decision Trees,
现在 为了进一步学习决策树
we need to learn an important concept called entropy.
我们需要学习一个重要的概念 熵
Entropy comes from physics and to explain it,
熵是一个物理学概念
we'll use the example of the three states of water.
我们将利用水的三态为例来解释这一概念
These are solid, which is ice,
水的三态也就是固态水 即冰
liquid, and gas, which is water vapor.
液态水和气态水 即水蒸气
Let's think of the particles inside ice, water, and vapor.
我们考虑一下冰 水和水蒸气中的粒子
Ice is pretty rigid in that its particles don't have many places to go.
由于冰中的粒子活动空间较小 其结构比较坚固
They mostly stay where they are.
粒子大多都固定不动
Water is a little less rigid in which a particle has a few places to move around.
液态水的结构坚固程度次之 粒子有一定的活动空间
And water vapor is in the other end of the spectrum.
而水蒸气的结构则处于另一个极端
A particle has many possibilities of where to go and can move around a lot.
一个粒子的去向有多种可能性 可经常移动
So, entropy measures precisely this,
同理 熵可以精准地测量
how much freedom does a particle have to move around?
一个粒子移动的自由程度
Thus, the entropy of ice is low,
因此 固态冰的熵很低
the entropy of liquid water is medium,
液态水的熵居中
and the entropy of water vapor is high.
水蒸气的熵最高
The notion of entropy can also work in probability.
熵的概念也可以用概率解释
Let's look at these three configurations of balls inside buckets.
我们来看看桶内球的三种配置
The first bucket has four red balls.
第一个桶内有四个红球
The second one has three red and one blue,
第二个桶内有三个红球和一个蓝球
and the third one has two red and two blue.
第三个桶内有两个红球和两个蓝球
And let's say balls from each color are completely indistinguishable.
假设每种颜色的球完全无法区分
So we could say that entropy is given by how much
因此 如果我们把这些球摆成一条直线
balls are allowed to move around if we put them in a line.
熵就是这些球移动的自由程度
We can see that the first bucket is very rigid.
第一个桶的结构较为固定
No matter how we organize the balls,
无论我们如何摆放这些球
we always get the same state,
它们总是处于同一状态
so it has low entropy.
因此它的熵最低
In the second one, we can reorganize the balls in four ways,
在第二个桶中 我们有四种方式摆放这些球
so it has medium entropy.
因此它的熵居中
For the third one, we have six ways of reorganizing the balls,
而在第三个桶中 我们有六种重组球的方法
so it has high entropy.
因此其熵最高
This is not the exact definition of entropy,
这并不是熵最准确的定义
but it gives us an idea,
但它给了我们这样一种观点
that the more rigid the set is or the more homogeneous,
集合越稳固或越具有同类性
the less entropy you'll have, and vice versa.
其熵越低 反之亦然
Another way to see entropy is in terms of knowledge.
另一种看待熵的方法是依据知识
If we were to pick a random ball from each of the buckets,
如果我们要从每个水桶中随机选出一个球
how much do we know about the color of this ball?
我们有多大可能知道球的颜色
In the first bucket, we know for sure that the ball is red,
在第一个桶中 我们知道该球的颜色必然是红色
so we have high knowledge.
所以其知识较高 00:01:53,944 --&gt; 00:01:58,519. 在第二个桶中 该球为红色的可能性很大 而为蓝色的可能性较小
So if we bet that it's red,
即 如果我们认定该球为红色
we'll be right most of the time.
则大多数情况下 我们是对的
So we have medium knowledge of the color of the ball.
因此我们对该球的颜色的知识居中
In the third bucket, we know much less since it's equally likely to be blue or red.
而在第三个桶中 该球颜色为红色和为蓝色的可能性一样大
So here, we have low knowledge.
因此 其知识较低
And it turns out that knowledge and entropy are opposites.
结果显示熵和知识相反
The more knowledge one has,
一个集合的知识越高
the less entropy, and vice versa.
其熵越低 反之亦然
Thus, we conclude that the first bucket has low entropy,
因此 可以总结出第一个桶的熵较低
the second one has medium entropy,
第二个桶的熵居中
and the third one has high entropy.
而第三个桶的熵较高
Now when I say opposites,
现在 当我说相反的时候
I don't mean additive inverse or multiplicative inverses.
我并不是说加法逆或者乘法逆
I only mean it in the colloquial sense of the word.
我只是指其口头意义
When one of them is big,
即当一个值较大时
then the other one is small, and vice versa.
另一个值会较小 反之亦然
Over the next few videos,
在接下来的几个视频中
we'll cook up a formula for entropy,
我们会制定一个熵的公式
namely, one that gives us low,
即 能为这些桶
medium, and high values for these buckets.
赋予较高 中等或较低值的公式